Kitemaug Press Collection
Kitemaug Press Collection
1967-2006
Kitemaug Press.
1 linear ft.
Miniature books, broadsides, miscellaneous sheets and other items printed by the Kitemaug Press of Spartanburg, South Carolina. Also information about Frank Anderson, owner/printer at Kitemaug and Librarian at Wofford College.
1514356
Biographical History
The Kitemaug Press is a small private press located in Spartanburg, South Carolina and specializing in fine letterpress printing, particularly of miniature books. The owner, proprietor, and primary printer is Frank J. Anderson, bibliophile, printer, and librarian at Wofford College.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Kitemaug Press Collection consists of miniature books and other items printed by the press, along with a small amount of publicity, both for individual titles and for the press as a whole. The collection also includes some pieces of correspondence from, and an essay by, owner and printer Frank J. Anderson as well as some Anderson / Wofford College material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Items are arranged alphabetically by type and within that (where possible) chronologically.
Related Material
has a wide range of material relating to small presses, private presses and fine printing in both our manuscript collections and our Rare Books holdings. Please refer to to locate other manuscript material and to to locate published and cataloged items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Anderson, Frank J.; Kitemaug Press.; Fine books.; Letterpress printing -- South Carolina.; Miniature books -- Specimens.; Printers -- South Carolina.; Private press books.; Private presses -- South Carolina.; Small presses -- South Carolina.; Spartanburg (S.C.) -- Imprints.; Advertisements.; Broadsides (notices); Correspondence.; Fliers (printed matter); Pamphlets.; Woodcuts (prints); Printers.; Printing.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from Rare Books, 2008. Originally gift of Frank J. Anderson.
Inventory
- Printed material
  - Books and booklets, 1972; 1979,; 1981,; undated; 4 items (Box 1)
    Specimens of type available at the Wofford Library Press, undated; Private presses in the southeastern United States, 1972; The Wofford College Campus Club cookbook, 1979; Notes on the human condition, 1981
  - Miniature books
    - 1967, 2 items (Box 2)
      Saint Arithmeticus; Kitemaug Mini-posters
    - 1968, 1 item (Box 2)
      Bonnie and Clyde
    - 1969, 1 item (Box 2)
      The woodpecker husband
    - 1979, 1 item (Box 2)
      Un pequeño libro do cocina
    - 1981, 1 item (Box 2)
      A visit from St. Nicholas
    - 1982, 3 items (Box 2)
      Christmas carols; Floral pieces of the altar; Sayings of G. Stein
    - 1984, 1 item (Box 2)
      Latin jive
    - 1985, 4 items (Box 2)
      Executive guide book; Faithful Fido; Shorty's dilemma, or, An incident at the Flying W Ranch; Signs of the Zodiac
    - 1986, 1 item (Box 2)
      Andy's bread book
    - 1987, 8 items (Box 2)
      Erasmus on studies; Letter to Bushrod from George Washington; Secret; Cats; Gaggle; Glimpses of Spartanburg; The herd moves south; The watchers
    - 1988, 3 items (Box 2)
      Outrageous cat tales; The world's teeniest tiniest book; Symbols of the Zodiac calendar
    - 1989, 3 items (Box 2)
      Cincinatti observed; Custody of books; A printer's calenadar for 1989
    - 1990, 3 items (Box 2)
      A girlie calendar for 1990; Glasgow, U.S.A.; Trees and stockings
    - 1991, 3 items (Box 2)
      Wm. Parks, printer; Catherine's counting book; Book lover's calendar
    - 1992, 2 items (Box 2)
      Heathen hangover; San Diego
    - 1993, 4 items (Box 2)
      Book lover's calendar; The stork; The wisdom sayings of Fu Ling; The ferris wheel
    - 1994, 5 items (Box 2)
      My friend Jerry; Tabitha's tale; 50: February 17, 1944 - February 17, 1994; The other Ottawas; An artist's calendar
    - 1995, 2 items (Box 2)
      Bread; Wine; Book lover's calendar
    - 1996, 3 items (Box 2)
      The cat lady; The gambler; Book lover's calendar
    - 1997, 2 items (Box 2)
      The skunk story; Book lover's calendar
    - 1998, 3 items (Box 2)
      Christmas images; A Hatphabet; Book lover's calendar
    - 1999, 6 items (Box 2)
      Book plates (2 copies); Blues; Book lover's calendar; Answers to life's questions; Eine kleine Deutsche worterbuch
    - 2000, 3 items (Box 2)
      The three bears' stories; Book lover's calendar; Maunderings
    - 2001, 2 items (Box 2)
      David's 23rd psalm; Some facts about Indiana
    - 2002, 3 items (Box 2)
      Book lover's calendar; Books; Between us girls
    - 2003, 3 items (Box 2)
      Book lover's calendar; Mother Goose rhymes; Goldie Lox and los tres osos
    - 2004, 1 item (Box 2)
      Excerpts from the book of Zebaniah
    - 2005, 6 items (Box 2)
      Book lover's calendar (2 copies); Cats: A gallery; A cockamamie ABC; The golden years blues
    - 2006, 3 items (Box 2)
      Art; A fairy tale retold (includes clipped statement from satisfied customer); Simfonia in a time of chaos
  - Pamphlets, 1974; 1975,; 1985,; 1988,; undated; 5 items (Box 1)
    Scenario (mock lecture about mail art), undated; The numbers game, 1974; Artists thinking about art, 1985; Something of myself, 1975; The year of the dragon, 1988
  - Portfolios, 1976; 1983,; undated; 4 items (Box 1)
    Thigh whackers, 1976; Mill Village suite, 1983 (2 copies); A treasury of southern Yankee recipes, undated
  - Miscellaneous, 1974; 1978-1980,; 1982,; 1986,; 2005,; undated; variety of single-sheet items, including poems, sayings, broadsides, woodcuts and other items produced by the press (Box 1)
- Publicity
  - Exhibit catalogs for Miniature Book Exhibition, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, small printed ads for specific books, for the Miniature Book Society, for the press; book lists; article in Sandlapper magazine (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence, Frank Anderson, 1969; 1992-2006 (Box 1)
  - Essay by Frank Anderson, "War: A Fugue", 2003; in reference to the war in Iraq (Box 1)
  - Frank Anderson / Wofford College miscellany, 1967-1969; article about Anderson's printing course, newsletter "Wofford Bibliopoly" by Anderson, college bulletin, etc. (Box 1)